Funding for this program is provided by
Additional funding provided by
Today we turn to Kant's reply to Aristotle.
Kant thinks that Aristotle just made a mistake.
It's one thing, Kant says, to
support a fair framework of rights
within which people can pursue their
own conceptions of the good life.
It's something else,
it's something that runs down the line,
it's the risk of coercion to
base law or principles of justice
on any particular conception of the good life.
You remember Aristotle says,
in order to investigate the ideal constitution,
we have first to figure
out the best way to live.
Kant would reject that idea.
He says that constitutions and laws
and rights should not embody or affirm
or promote any particular way of life.
That's at odds with freedom.
For Aristotle.
The whole point of law,
the purpose of the polis,
is to shape character,
to cultivate the virtue of citizens,
to inculcate civic excellence,
to make possible a good way of life.
That's what he tells us in the politics.
For Kant, on the other hand,
the purpose of law,
the point of a constitution,
is not to inculcate or to promote virtue,
it's to set up a fair framework of rights
within which citizens may be free to pursue
their own conceptions of the good for themselves.
So we see the difference in their theories of justice,
we see the difference in their account of law,
or the role of a constitution,
the point of politics,
and underlying these differences
are two different accounts of what
it means to be a good person.
To be a free person.
For Aristotle,
we're free insofar as we have the capacity
to realize our potential.
And that leads us to the question of fit.
Fit between persons and the
roles that are appropriate to them.
Figuring out what I'm cut out for.
That's what it means to lead a free life.
To live up to my potential.
Kant rejects that idea
and instead substitutes his
famously demanding notion of freedom
as the capacity to act autonomously.
Freedom means acting according to a law I give myself.
Freedom as autonomy.
Part of the appeal,
part of the moral force
of the view of Kant and of Rawls
consists in
the conception of the person
as a free and independent self
capable of choosing his or her own ends.
The image of the self as free and independent
offers, if you think about it,
a powerful, liberating vision
because what it says is
that as free moral persons
we are not bound
by any ties
of history
or of tradition
or of inherited status
that we haven't chosen for ourselves.
And so we're unbound by any moral ties
prior to our choosing them.
And that means
that means that we are
free and independent sovereigns
and we are free and independent sovereign selves.
We're the authors of the only obligations
that constrain us.
The communitarian critics
of Kantian and Rawlsian liberalism
acknowledge that there is something
powerful and inspiring
in that account of freedom,
the free, independent, choosing self.
But they argue
that it misses something.
It misses a whole dimension
of moral life and even political life.
It can't make sense of our moral experience
because it can't account
for certain moral and political obligations
that we commonly recognize and even prize.
And these include obligations of membership,
loyalty, solidarity,
and other moral ties
that may claim us for reasons
that we can't trace
to an act of consent.
Alasdair MacIntyre
gives an account
what he calls a narrative conception
of the self.
It's a different account
Human beings are essentially
storytelling creatures,
MacIntyre argues.
That means I can only answer the question
what am I to do
if I can answer the prior question
of what story or stories
do I find myself apart?
That's what he means by
the narrative conception of the self.
What does this have to do
with the idea of community
and belonging?
MacIntyre says this,
once you accept this narrative aspect
of moral reflection,
you will notice
that we can never seek for the good
or exercise the virtues
only as individuals.
We all approach our circumstance
as bearers of particular social identities.
I am someone's son or daughter,
a citizen of this or that city.
I belong to this clan,
that tribe,
this nation.
Hence, MacIntyre argues,
what is good for me
is to be a part of the community.
And that's what he means
by the narrative conception of the self.
What is good for me
has to be the good
for someone who inhabits these roles.
I inherit from the past
of my family, my city, my tribe, my nation,
a variety of debts, inheritances,
expectations and obligations.
These constitute the given of my life,
my moral starting point.
This is, in part, what gives my life
its moral particularity.
That's the narrative conception
of the self.
And it's a conception that sees the self
as claimed or encumbered,
at least to some extent,
by the history, the tradition,
the communities of which it's a part.
We can't make sense of our lives,
not only as a psychological matter,
but also as a moral matter
in thinking what we ought to do
without attending
to these features about us.
Now, McIntyre recognizes
that this narrative account,
this picture of the encumbered self,
puts his account at odds with
contemporary liberalism and individualism.
From the standpoint of individualism,
I am what I myself choose to be.
I may biologically be my father's son,
but I can't be held responsible
for what he did
unless I choose to assume
such responsibility.
I can't be held responsible
for what my country does
or has done
unless I choose to assume
such responsibility.
But McIntyre says this reflects
a certain kind of moral shallowness,
even blindness.
It's a blindness at odds with the full measure
of responsibility,
which sometimes he says involves
collective responsibility
or responsibilities that may flow
from historic memories.
And he gives some examples.
Such individualism is expressed
by those contemporary Americans
who deny any responsibility
for the effects of slavery
upon black Americans, saying,
I never owned any slaves.
Or the young German
who believes that having been born
after 1945
means that what Nazis did to Jews
has no moral relevance
to his relationship
to his Jewish contemporaries.
McIntyre says all of these attitudes
of historical amnesia
amount to a kind of moral abdication.
Once you see that who we are
and what it means
to sort out our obligations
can't be separated,
from the life histories
that define us.
The contrast, he says,
with the narrative account is clear.
For the story of my life
is always embedded in the story
of those communities
from which I derive my identity.
I am born with a past
and to try to cut myself off
from that past
is to deform my present relationships.
So there you have in McIntyre
a strong statement of the idea
that the self can't be detached,
shouldn't be detached
from its particular ties of membership,
history, story, narrative.
Now I want to get your reactions
to the communitarian critique
of the individualist
or the voluntarist,
the unencumbered self.
But let's make it clear
and concrete
so that you can react
to more than just the theory of it
by looking at
the two different accounts
of moral and political obligation
that arise
depending on which of these conceptions
of the person
one accepts.
On the liberal conception,
moral and political obligations arise
in one of two ways.
There are natural duties
that we owe human beings as such,
duties of respect for persons qua persons.
These obligations are universal.
Then, as Rawls points out,
there are also voluntary obligations,
obligations that we owe
to particular others
insofar as we have agreed,
whether through a promise
or a deal or a contract.
Now the issue between
the liberal and communitarian accounts of the self,
is there another category of obligation or not?
The communitarian says there is.
There is a third category
that might be called obligations of solidarity
or loyalty or membership.
The communitarian argues that
construing all obligations,
as either natural duties
or voluntary obligations,
fails to capture obligations
of membership or solidarity.
Loyalties whose moral force
consists partly in the fact
that living by them
is inseparable from understanding ourselves
as the particular persons we are.
What would be some examples?
And then I want to see
how you would react to them.
Examples.
Examples of obligations of membership
that are particular
but don't necessarily flow from consent
but rather from membership,
narrative, community, one's situation.
The most common examples
are ones to do with the family.
The relation between parents and children,
for example.
Suppose there were two children drowning.
You could save only one of them.
One was your child,
the other was a stranger's child.
Would you have an obligation
to flip a coin?
Or would there be something morally obtuse
if you didn't rush to save your child?
Now you may say,
well, parents have agreed
to have their children.
So take the other case.
The case of children's obligation
for their parents.
Now we don't choose our parents.
We don't even choose to have parents.
There is that asymmetry.
And yet,
consider two aging parents,
one of them yours,
the other a stranger's.
Doesn't it make moral sense
to think that you have a greater obligation
to look after your aged parent
than to flip a coin?
Or to help the strangers?
Now, is this traceable to consent?
Not likely.
Or take a couple of political examples.
During World War II,
French resistance pilots
flew bombing raids over occupied France.
One day,
one of the pilots received his targets
and noticed
that the village he was being asked to bomb
was his home village.
He refused,
not disputing that it was as necessary
as the target he bombed yesterday.
He refused on the ground
that he couldn't bring himself.
It would be a special moral crime
for him to bomb his people,
even in a cause that he supported,
the cause of liberating France.
Now, do we admire that?
If we do,
the communitarian argues,
it's because we do recognize
obligations of solidarity.
Take another example.
Some years ago,
there was a famine in Ethiopia.
Hundreds of thousands of people were starving.
The Israeli government organized an airlift
to rescue Ethiopian Jews.
They didn't have the capacity
to rescue everyone in Ethiopia.
They rescued several hundred Ethiopian Jews.
Now,
what's your moral assessment?
Is that a kind of
morally troubling partiality?
A kind of prejudice?
Or,
as the Israeli government thought,
is there a special obligation of solidarity
that this airlift properly responded to?
Well, that takes us to the broader question
of patriotism.
What, morally speaking,
is to be said for patriotism?
There are two towns named Franklin.
One is Franklin, Texas,
and the other is just across the Rio Grande River,
Franklin, Mexico.
What is the moral significance
of national boundaries?
Why is it,
or is it the case,
that we as Americans
have a greater responsibility
for the health and the education
and the welfare and public provision
for people who live in Franklin, Texas,
than equally needy people
just across the river
living in Franklin, Mexico?
According to the communitarian account,
membership does matter.
And the reason patriotism
is at least potentially a virtue
is that it is an expression
of the obligations of citizenship.
How many are sympathetic to the idea
that there is this third category of obligation,
the obligations of solidarity or membership?
How many are sympathetic to that idea?
And how many are critical of that idea?
How many think all obligations
can be accounted for
in the first two ways?
All right, let's hear from the critics
of the communitarian idea first.
Yes.
My biggest concern with
the idea of having obligations
because you're a member of something
or because of solidarity
is that it seems that
if you accept those obligations
as being sort of morally binding,
then there's a greater current
of overlapping obligations,
a greater occurrence of good versus good.
And I don't know if this sort of framework
allows us to choose between them.
Good. And what's your name?
Patrick.
So you worry that if we recognize
obligations of membership or solidarity,
since we inhabit different communities,
their claims might conflict.
And what would we do
if we have competing obligations?
Yes.
Well, one solution is that
we could view ourselves as
ultimately members of the human community
and that then within that
we have all these smaller spheres
of that, you know, I am American
or I am a student at Harvard.
And so the most important community
to be obligated to
is the community of human beings.
And then from there you can sort of evaluate
which other ones are most important to you.
So the most universal...
And what's your name?
Nicola.
So Nicola, you say the most universal community
we inhabit, the community of humankind,
always takes precedence.
Yes.
Patrick, are you satisfied?
No.
謝謝
Why not?
It seems rather arbitrary that we should choose
the universal obligation over the more specific obligation.
I might also say that I should be obligated first
to the most specific of my obligations.
For instance, take my family
as a small unit of solidarity.
Perhaps I should be first obligated to that unit,
and then perhaps to the unit of my town,
and then my country, and then the human race.
Good, thank you.
I want to hear from another critic
of the communitarian view.
We have the objection, well, what if goods collide?
Who objects to the whole idea of it?
Who sees patriotism as just a kind of prejudice
that ideally we should overcome?
Yes.
Patriotism reflects a community membership.
That's a given.
I think the problem is that
whereas some memberships are natural narratives,
the narrative of citizenship is a constructed one,
and I think a false one,
because as the river is just a historical accident,
it makes no sense that because the lottery of birth
threw me into the United States as opposed to Mexico,
that that's the membership that
I should be a part of.
Good, and what's your name?
Elizabeth. Elizabeth.
Who has a reply?
Yes.
I think in general, we have to ask,
where do our moral obligations arise from anyway?
And I think basically there'd be two places
from which they could arise.
One would be kin, and another one would be reciprocity.
And the closer you are associated to other people,
there's a natural reciprocity there
in terms of having interactions with those people.
You interact with the neighbors,
you interact with your friends,
you interact with your friends.
You interact with the neighbors on your street,
with the other people in your country
through economic arrangements.
But I don't know, and you don't know those people
in Franklin, Texas, any more than you know
the people in Franklin, Mexico, do you?
Presumably, you're naturally more connected
with the people in your own country
in terms of interaction and trade
than you are with people in other countries.
Good. Who else?
Go ahead.
Yeah, I think that a
lot of the basis for patriotism
can be compared to school spirit
or even house spirit that we see
here where freshmen are sorted into houses
and then within a day they have developed
some sort of attachment or pride associated with that house.
And so I think that
we can probably draw a distinction
between a moral obligation for communitarian beliefs
and sort of just a sentimental emotional attachment.
Good. Wait. Stay there. What's your name?
Rena.
What about, go back to my example about the obligation
of the child to the parent.
Would you say the same thing there?
It's just a, may or
may not be a sentimental thing,
but it has no moral weight?
Well, I mean, I'm not entirely certain that accident
in the initial stage is something that will preclude,
like, moral obligations later.
So, you know, just because we
are randomly sorted into a house
or just because we don't choose who our parents are
or what country we're born into
doesn't necessarily mean that we won't, like,
develop an obligation based on
some type of benefit, I guess.
Just sort of a...
So your obligation to your aged parent
that's greater than to aged parents around the world
is only because and insofar as you're repaying a benefit
that your parent gave you when you were growing up?
Yeah, I mean, I would say that
if you look at cases of adoption
where, you know, you have a biological parent somewhere else
that you don't interact with,
and then you have a parent,
you know, who adopted you, most people would say that,
if you had to pick between
them in the case of, you know,
aging parents, that your obligation would lie more
with the person who raised you
and who had exchanges with you meaningfully.
May I ask you one more question about the parent?
Sure.
Do you think that a person
with a bad parent owes them less?
I don't know, because I've never had a bad parent.
I think that's a good place to end.
Thank you.
We'll continue with this next time.
If I were working on
an ECK problem set, for example,
and I saw that my roommate was cheating,
that might be a bad thing for him to do,
but I wouldn't turn him in.
You would not turn him in?
I wouldn't turn him in, and I think that,
I would argue that's the right thing to do
because of my obligation to him, you know.
You don't have a duty to tell the truth,
to report someone who cheated.
Today, I'd like to take,
I'd like to consider the strongest objections to the idea
that there are obligations of solidarity or membership.
Then I want to see if
those objections can be met successfully.
One objection emerged in the discussion last time.
Patrick said, well,
if obligations flow away,
if we go from community membership and identity,
we inhabit multiple communities,
doesn't that mean that
our obligations will sometimes conflict?
So that's one possible objection.
And then Rena said,
these examples meant to bring out the moral force
of solidarity and membership,
examples about parents and children,
about the French resistance fighter
asked to bomb his own village in drawing back,
about the airlift by Israel of Ethiopian Jews.
These examples, they may be intuitively evocative,
Rena said, but really they're pointing to
matters of emotion, matters of sentiment,
not true moral obligations.
And then there were a number of objections,
not necessarily to patriotism as such,
but to patriotism understood as
an obligation of solidarity and membership
beyond consent.
This objection
allowed that there can be obligations
to the communities we inhabit, including
obligations of patriotism,
but this objection argued that
all of the obligations of patriotism
or of community or membership
are actually based on liberal ideas
and perfectly compatible with them.
Consent, either implicit or explicit,
or reciprocity.
Julia Rathow, for example, on the website
said that liberalism can indeed be
endorsed patriotism as a voluntary moral obligation.
Patriotism and familial love
both fall under this category,
because after all, Julia points out,
the Kantian framework allows people free reign
to choose to express virtues such as these
if they want to.
So you don't need the idea
of a nonvoluntary particular moral obligation
to capture the moral force of community values.
Where's Julia?
Okay.
So, did I summarize that fairly?
There is action.
Julia actually is in line with
what Rawls says about this very topic.
You weren't aware of that.
You came up with it on your own.
That's pretty good.
Rawls says, when he's discussing political obligation,
he says it's one thing if someone runs for office
or enlists in the military.
They're making a voluntary choice.
But Rawls says there is, I believe,
no political obligation, strictly speaking,
for citizens generally,
because it's not clear what is the requisite binding action
and who has performed it.
So Rawls acknowledges
that for ordinary citizens,
there is no political obligation
except insofar as some particular citizen
willingly, through an act of consent,
undertakes or chooses such an obligation.
That's in line with Julia's point.
It's related to another objection
that people have raised,
which is it's perfectly possible
to recognize particular obligations
to one's family or to one's country,
provided honoring those obligations
doesn't require you to violate any of the natural duties
or requirements of universal respect
for persons qua persons.
So that's consistent with the idea
that we can choose, if we want to,
to express a loyalty to our country
or to our people or to our family,
provided we don't do any injustice
within the framework, acknowledging the priority,
that is,
that we have universal duties.
The one objection that I didn't mention
is the view of those who say
that obligations of membership
really are a kind of collective selfishness.
Why should we honor them?
Isn't it just a kind of prejudice?
So what I'd like to do,
perhaps if those of you who have agreed,
who wrote and who have agreed
to press these objections,
perhaps if you could gather down
all together, we'll form a team,
as we did once before,
and we'll see if you can respond
to those who want to defend
patriotism conceived as a communal obligation.
Now, there were a number of people
who argued in defense
of patriotism
as the communitarian view conceives it.
So let me go down now and join the critics,
the critics of communitarianism,
if there's a microphone that we could use somewhere.
Okay, thanks, Kate.
Who, as the critics of patriotism,
communal patriotism,
gather their forces here?
Patrick, if you want to, you can join as well,
or Rena, others who have spoken
or addressed this question are free to join in.
But I would like to hear now
from those of you who defend patriotism
and defend it as a moral obligation
that can't be translated back into
purely consent-based terms,
can't be translated into liberal terms.
Where's A.J. Kumar?
A.J., everybody seems to know you.
All right.
Let's hear from A.J.
You said,
in the same way I feel
I owe more to my family
than to the general community,
I owe more to my country
than to humanity in general,
because my country holds a great stake in my identity.
It is not prejudice for me to love my country
unless it is prejudice for me
to love my parents more than somebody else's.
So, A.J., what would you say to this group?
Stand up.
I think that there's some fundamental
moral obligation that comes from
a communitarian responsibility
to people and groups that form your identity.
I mean, even, like, I'll
give the example that, you know,
there are a lot of
things about our government right now
that I'm not in favor of,
but part of my identity is
that America values a free society
where we can object to certain things,
and I think that's an expression of patriotism as well.
And, you know, I go back to the parent example,
or even at Harvard, I think, you know,
I owe more to my roommates
because they make up my identity
than I do to the Harvard community as a whole,
and I think that applies to our country
because there are certain things that growing up here,
yes, we can't choose it, we can't choose our parents,
things like that, but it
makes up part of our identity.
Okay, who would like to take that on?
Ike?
Yeah, about the obligation to others
simply by virtue of being in their, their,
being influenced by them.
I'm a German citizen,
and if I had been born 80 years earlier,
then I would have been a citizen of Nazi Germany,
and for some reason, I just don't
think that I would have to feel obligated
towards Germany because I had
benefited from actions of Nazis.
I mean, I guess my response to that would be
you have hundreds of thousands of
protesters in the United States right now
who hold up signs that say peace is patriotic,
and I'm sure there are people in
this room who don't agree with that.
I personally do,
and I would say that they're strongly opposed
to rejecting to basically everything the
Bush administration is doing right now,
but they still consider themselves loving their country
because they're furthering the cause of what
they see as best for the country,
and I tend to agree
with that as a patriotic movement.
Well, but how's that then,
how do you still favor your country?
How's that still patriotic?
I mean, isn't that more a sentimental attachment?
Where's the obligation there?
Reina?
Yeah, not to bring this back to John Locke,
but I would like to
bring this back to John Locke.
I mean, in his conception of, you know,
when people join society,
there's still some outlet.
Like, if you're not satisfied with your society,
you know, you do have a means of exit,
even though we had a lot of
concerns about how you're born in it
and it's not very feasible,
he still provides that option.
If we want to say that your
obligation to society is a moral one,
that means that prior to knowing exactly
what that society's going to be like
or what your position's going to be in that society,
that means that you have a binding obligation to, like,
a completely unknown body that could be, you know,
completely foreign to all of your personal beliefs
or, you know, what you would hold to be correct.
Do you think that that
kind of communal obligation or patriotism
means writing the community a blank moral check?
Basically, yeah.
Like, I think that we can, you know,
I think it's reasonable to say that as you grow
and as you develop within that community,
that you acquire some type
of obligation based on reciprocity,
but to say that you
have a moral obligation, I think,
requires a stronger justification.
Good.
Who else?
Anyone else like to address that?
I guess we could say that you could argue
that you're morally obliged to society
by the fact that there is this reciprocity.
I think it's the idea that, you know,
we participate in society, we pay our taxes, we vote.
This is why we could say
that we owe something to society.
But beyond that, I don't think there's anything inherent
in the fact that we
are members of the society itself
that we owe it anything.
I think insofar as the society gives us a voice,
gives us something, gives us protection, safety, security,
then we owe the society something,
but nothing beyond what we give the society.
Who wants to take that on?
Rahul?
I don't think we give the community
a blank moral check in that sense.
I think we only give it a blank moral check
when we abdicate our sense of civic responsibility
and when we say that the debate doesn't matter
because patriotism is a vice.
I think that patriotism is important
because it gives us a sense of community,
a sense of common civic virtue
that we can engage in the issues.
Even if you don't agree with
the way the government is acting,
you can still love your country
and hate the way it's acting.
And I think because out of that love of country,
you can debate with other people
and have respect for their views,
but still engage in the debate.
If you just say that,
you know, patriotism is a vice,
you drop out of that
debate and you cede the ground
to people who are more fundamentalist,
who have a stronger view,
and who may coerce the community.
Instead, we should engage the other members of the community
on that same moral ground.
Well, now this, what we hear from Ajay and Rahul
is a very pluralistic, argumentative,
critically-minded patriotism,
whereas what we hear from Ike
and the critics of patriotism here
is the worry that to take patriotic obligation
in a communal way, seriously,
involves a kind of loyalty
that doesn't let us just pick and choose
among the beliefs or actions or practices of our country.
What more, what's left of loyalty
if all we're talking about,
Ajay and Rahul, if all we're talking about
is loyalty to principles of justice
that may happen to be embodied in our community
or not, as the case may be,
and if not, then we can reject its course.
I don't know, I've sort of given a reply.
I got carried away, I'm sorry.
Who would like...
Go ahead, Julia.
Yeah, I think that patriotism,
you need to define what that is.
It sounds like, you know, you would normally think
that we are given a more weak definition here,
patriotism, amongst us,
but it almost sounds like your definition is merely
to have some sort of civic involvement in debating
within your society,
and I think that that kind of undermines
maybe some of the moral worth of patriotism
as a virtue as well.
I think if you can consent
to a stronger form of patriotism
if you want, that's a stronger, I guess, moral obligation
than even what you're suggesting.
What we really need to sharpen the issue
is an example from the defenders of communitarianism
of a case where loyalty can actually compete with
and possibly outweigh universal principles of justice.
Isn't that what...
That's the test they really need to meet, isn't it?
All right, so that's the test you need to meet,
or any among you who would like to defend
obligations of membership or solidarity
independent of ones that happen to embody just principles.
Who has an example of a kind of loyalty
that can and should compete with universal moral claims,
respect for persons?
Go ahead.
Yeah, if I were working on
an EC problem set, for example,
and I saw that my roommate was cheating,
that might be a bad thing for him to do,
but I wouldn't turn him in.
You would not turn him in?
I wouldn't turn him in, and I think that...
I would argue that's the right thing to do
because of my obligation to him, you know?
It may be wrong,
but that's what I would do,
and I think that's what
most people would do as well.
All right, that's...
Now, there's a fair test.
He's not slipping out by saying
he's invoking in the name of community
some universal principles of justice.
What's your name?
Stay there.
It's Dan.
Dan?
So what do people think about Dan's case?
That's a harder case for
the ethic of loyalty, isn't it?
But a truer test?
How many agree with Dan's case?
Yes.
How many disagree with Dan?
So loyalty...
Dan, loyalty has its part of sense.
How many disagree with Dan?
Peggy?
Well, I agree with Dan,
but I agree that it's a choice that we make,
but it's not necessarily right or wrong.
I mean, I'm agreeing that I'm going to make
that choice because I'm going to choose my roommate,
but I also recognize that that choice isn't morally right.
So you're still translating...
Even Dan's loyalty, you're saying,
well, that's a matter of choice,
but what's the right thing to do?
Most people put up their hands saying
Dan would be right to stand by his roommate
and not turn him in.
Yes, go ahead.
Also, I think as a roommate,
you have insider information,
and that might not be something you want to use.
That might be something unfair to hold against.
You know, you're spending that much time with a roommate.
Obviously, you're going to learn things about him,
and I don't think it's fair to reveal that
to a greater community.
But it's loyalty, Wojtek.
You agree with Dan that loyalty
is the ethic at stake here.
Absolutely.
You don't have a duty to tell the truth,
to report someone who cheated?
Not if you've been advantaged
into getting that kind of information.
Before our critics of patriotism leave,
I want to give you another version,
a more public example of what we'll...
I guess we should call it Dan's dilemma.
Dan's dilemma of loyalty.
And I want to get
the reaction of people to this.
This came up a few years ago,
in Massachusetts.
Does anyone know who this man is?
Billy Bulger.
Billy Bulger, that's right.
Who is Billy Bulger?
He was president of the Massachusetts State Senate
for many years,
one of the most powerful politicians in Massachusetts.
And then he became president
of the University of Massachusetts.
Now, Billy Bulger,
did you hear the story about him
that bears on Dan's dilemma?
Billy Bulger has a brother
named Whitey Bulger.
And this is Whitey Bulger.
His brother, Whitey,
is on the FBI's most wanted list,
alleged to be a notorious gang leader in Boston,
responsible for many murders,
and now a fugitive from justice.
But when the U.S. Attorney,
they called Billy Bulger,
then the president of the University of Massachusetts,
before the grand jury,
and wanted information on the whereabouts of his brother,
this fugitive.
And he refused to give it.
U.S. Attorney said,
just to be clear, Mr. Bulger,
you feel more loyalty to your brother
than to the people of the Commonwealth of Massachusetts?
And here's what Billy Bulger said,
I never thought of it that way,
but I do have a loyalty to my brother.
I care about him.
I hope that I'm never helpful to anyone against him.
I don't have an obligation
to help anyone catch my brother.
Dan, you would agree.
How many would agree with the position
of Billy Bulger?
Let me give one other example,
and then we'll let the critics reply,
the critics of loyalty,
as we'll describe it.
Here's an even more fateful example
from a figure in American history,
Robert E. Lee.
Now, Robert E. Lee,
on the eve of the Civil War,
was an officer of the Union Army.
He opposed secession,
in fact regarded it as treason.
When war loomed,
Lincoln offered Lee
to be the commanding general
of the Union Army,
and Lee refused,
and he described in a letter to his sons
why he refused.
With all my devotion to the Union, he wrote,
I have not been able to make up my mind
to raise my hand against my relatives,
my children, my home.
By which he meant Virginia.
The Union Army
is a state of war.
The Union is dissolved.
I shall return to my native state
and share the miseries of my people,
save in her defense,
I will draw my sword no more.
Now here's a real test,
Dan,
for your principle of loyalty.
Because here
is the cause of the war against,
not only to save the Union,
but against slavery.
And Lee
will continue to
destroy Virginia
even though he doesn't share
the desire of the Southern states to secede.
Now the communitarian would say
there is something admirable in that,
whether or not the decision was ultimately right,
there's something admirable.
And the communitarian would say
we can't even make sense.
Rena, we can't make sense
that the claim of loyalty arising from
his sense of narrative of who he is,
is a moral, not just sentimental, emotional tug.
Alright, who would like to respond to Dan's
loyalty, to Billy Bulger's loyalty,
or to Robert E. Lee's loyalty
to Virginia? What do you say, Julia?
Okay, well, I think that this
is, these are some classic examples of,
you know, multiple spheres of influence
and that you have conflicting communities
that
your family and your country. I think
that's one reason why the idea of
choice in your obligation is so
important because how else can you
resolve this? You have, if you're morally
obligated and there's no way out of this
need for loyalty to both communities, you're
trapped, there's nothing you can do.
You have to make a choice and
I think that being able to
choose based on other characteristics and merely,
you know, the arbitrary fact that you're
a member of this community is important.
Otherwise it's left, I guess, randomness. Well,
Julia, the issue isn't
whether these, whether Dan makes a choice
or Billy Bulger or Robert E. Lee. Of
course they make a choice. The question is
on what grounds, on what principle should they choose?
The communitarian doesn't deny that there's
a choice to be made, the question
is
which choice, on what grounds and should loyalty
as such weigh?
Andre, now you want to, all right go ahead.
What do you say? Well I, one of
the things we've noticed in three examples, on the
is that the people have all chosen the most immediate
community of which they're a part, the more local one,
and I think there's something to be
said for that. It's not just random.
I mean, there doesn't seem to be a conflict because they
know which one is more important, and it's their family over
the ECTEN class, their state over their country,
and their family over the Commonwealth of Massachusetts.
So I think that's the
answer to which is more important.
You think that the local, the more
particular, is always the weightier morally, Andre?
Well, I mean, there seems to
be a trend in the three cases.
I would agree with that, I think, and I think
most of us would agree that your family takes precedence over
the United States, perhaps.
Which is why you go with Dan.
Dan, loyalty to the roommate over ECTEN and the truth.
Yeah, exactly.
I would, because I mean...
I mean truth telling, not the truth of ECTEN.
Yes.
All right, so we understand.
But on the same example in terms of family, you had cases
in the Civil War where brother was pitted against brother on both sides
of the war, where they chose country instead of family.
So I think the exact same war shows that
different people have different means of making these choices, and that
there is no one set of values or one set of
morality that
communitarians can stick to. And personally, I think that's the biggest problem
with communitarians, that we don't have one set of standard moral obligations.
And tell me your name.
Samantha.
So, Samantha, you agree with Patrick, Patrick's point the other day,
that there may be, if we allow obligations to be defined by
community identification or membership,
they may conflict, they may overlap, they may compete,
and there is no clear principle.
Andre says there's a clear principle, the most particular.
The other day, Nicola, who is sitting
over here, where's Nicola, said the most universal.
You're saying, Samantha,
the scale of the community as
such can't be the decisive moral factor.
So there has to be some other moral judgment.
All right, let's first, let's...
let our critics of communal patriotism, let's express our
appreciation and thank them for their having stood up and
responded to these arguments to find the issue.
Let's turn to the implications for justice
of the positions that we've heard discussed here.
One of the worries underlying these multiple objections
to the idea of loyalty or
membership as having independent moral weight
is that it seems to argue that there
is no way of finding principles of justice
that are detached from
conceptions of the good life as
they may be lived in any particular community.
Suppose the communitarian argument is right.
Suppose the priority of the right
over the good can't be sustained.
Suppose instead
that justice and rights unavoidably are bound up with
conceptions of the good.
Does that mean that
justice is
simply a
creature of convention of the values that happen to
prevail in any given community at any given time?
One of the writings we have among
the communitarian critics is by Michael Walser.
He draws the implications of justice this way.
Justice is relative to social
meanings. A given society is just
if its substantive life has lived in a certain
way, in a way that is faithful to the shared
understandings of the members.
So,
Walser's account seems to bear out the worry
that if we can't find independent principles of justice, independent that
is from conceptions of the good that prevail in any given community,
that we're simply left with justice
being a matter of fidelity or faithfulness
to the shared understandings or values or
conventions that prevail in any given society.
at any given time.
But is that an adequate way of thinking about justice?
Well, let's take a look at a short
clip from the documentary Eyes on the Prize.
Goes back in the 1950s in the South.
Here are some
situated American southerners who believe in the
tradition in the shared understandings of segregation.
Listen to the arguments they make about loyalty and tradition and see if they
don't make you uneasy about tying arguments about justice to the shared understandings or traditions.
that prevail in any given society at the moment.
Let's run the clip.
This land is composed of two different cultures.
A white culture and a colored culture.
And I've lived close to them all my life.
But I'm told now that we
mistreated them and that we must change.
And these changes are coming faster than I expected.
And I'm required to
make decisions on a basis of a
new way of thinking and it's difficult.
It's difficult for me.
It's difficult for all southerners.
Well, there you have it.
Narrative selves, situated selves, invoking tradition.
Doesn't that show us
that justice can't be tied to the
shared understandings of goods that prevail in
any given community at any given time?
Or is there a way of
rescuing that claim from this example?
Think about that question and
we'll return to it next time.
Don't miss the chance to interact
online with other viewers of Justice.
Join the conversation. Take a pop quiz.
Watch lectures you've missed and learn a lot more.
Visit JusticeHarvard.org. It's the right thing to do.
Have fun trying to close up on
your favorite막ع McDowell on how things are.
Well we've spent a full month of July,
amidst one-and-a-half of elastic
God speed events.
All allowed to not meet
one-and-a-half-year-olds and
and somebody you never met,
and you can't capture the
gradual change is
unpredictable and
this might mean
reaching out to
justice fighters and
facing criticism that
as aenerga
enters June because
we cannot
watershift
the
national
advocacy
of national
march
otto
Funding for this program is provided by...
Additional funding provided by...